<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Jiayee.net</title>
    <link>https://jiayee.net/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Jiayee.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 21:44:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jiayee.net/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixing a11y</title>
      <link>https://jiayee.net/2023/07/fixing-a11y/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 21:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiayee.net/2023/07/fixing-a11y/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d need to jump through many hoops to resolve an a11y issue in this site. Today, I realised I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to.
From my previous Lighthouse reports,
Heading elements are not in a sequentially-descending order
had been a thorn in the flesh. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to override the original styles of the headers. But I wanted my h2 to look like h3. I wanted my h3 to look like h5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Style Fixes 1</title>
      <link>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/style-fixes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 16:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/style-fixes-1/</guid>
      <description>I discovered there were some unexpected styles for &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt; in this site. This is due to Foundation&amp;rsquo;s default styles. The inline code style was fine, but the same style applied to code blocks (i.e. &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;), and that was not fine. There was also insufficient margin and padding for the code blocks. I inspected the &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; elements. I found out that Foundation was the culprit. It has been styling the &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; elements on top of what Hugo has in store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Theme</title>
      <link>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 12:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Hello to my new theme! Indeed&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;You Day&amp;rdquo; was yesterday, and I spent the day redesigning this site. I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased with the result. I was able to follow my hand-drawn wireframe to produce this theme. While this is a simple theme, I made sure to consider these things:
Little clutter Consistent margin between sections. The margin was 2rem between sections and 1rem between post metadata and content. Only 3 font sizes (Foundation&amp;rsquo;s h1, h3 and h5) Only 3 colours (background colour: #F5F5F5, font colour: #333333 and dark turquoise: #26867C) Reduction of eye strain with lower contrast of colours Colour-blind friendly Through this experience, I gained more exposure to Hugo and Foundation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
