<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>domains on Jiayee.net</title>
    <link>https://jiayee.net/tags/domains/</link>
    <description>Recent content in domains on Jiayee.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 21:31:40 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jiayee.net/tags/domains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare Workers</title>
      <link>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/cloudflare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 21:31:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/cloudflare-workers/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to put my short custom domain to good use. Cloudflare Workers is a quick &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; dirty way for me to do URL forwarding from various paths of jiay.ee without having to set up DNS records or page rules. The former requires domain verification, and social media websites do not support custom domains (why will they). The latter costs money (the first 3 page rules are free).
My worker was named &amp;quot;vanity&amp;quot; for obvious reasons and it sits at https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding my sites to Cloudflare</title>
      <link>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/adding-my-sites-to-cloudflare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 11:34:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/adding-my-sites-to-cloudflare/</guid>
      <description>I added my domains to Cloudflare. Cloudflare offers many cool features which my domain providers do not offer. Well, they did not need to offer those features. In Cloudflare, I get to see web traffic analytics, set up DNSSEC, configure network transport options and/or optimisations, run speed tests on my site, configure caching, run JavaScript workers and even restrict image hotlinking. This list is non-exhaustive. There are more features in the Pro and Enterprise subscriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom domains</title>
      <link>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/custom-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 01:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiayee.net/2020/09/custom-domains/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I purchased the jiayee.net domain. Yesterday, I purchased the jiay.ee domain. It was a novel experience for me. I last &amp;ldquo;purchased&amp;rdquo; a domain from Freenom about 3 years ago. Back then, I had the free domain point to my AWS EC2 public IP address. This week, my custom domains are pointing towards GitHub pages and Blogspot respectively.
For GitHub pages, I followed a guide which is similar to this one by Rich.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>